Guide to the Asian CineVision Records TAM.416
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Video Recordings
  - Video 225: CCTV, January 27, 1980; Cuid9271 (Box 91, Video cuid9271)
    This episode includes three parts: street interviews, a Hong Kong film, and an announcement section. In the street interviews, two hosts interview people about heat provision in their apartments. Interviewees complain about having difficulties getting heat in the winter, and they suggest it is landlords' responsibility to take care of this matter. The second part of the episode is an Allen Fong () film The Wild Child () (1977). The film depicts the ups and downs of a young boy's life who lives with his grandmother in a rural village.
    Format: Umatic, Duration: 57 minutes
  - Video 226: CCTV, February 3, 1980; Cuid9272 (Box 91, Video Cuid9272)
    This episode includes several parts: news reports on Chinese athletes visiting the United States and Chinese students having dinner gathering, a 26-minute Hong Kong film, coverage of a labor demonstration, and an announcement section. The first part reports the US-China Peoples Friendship Association receiving People's Republic of China athletes who for the first time attend the Winter Olympics. Interviews with athletes and officials from China are included. The second part covers a dinner gathering organized by the National Association of Chinese-Americans. The third part is an Allen Fong () film Song of Yuen Chau Chai () (1977), which depicts the lives of fishermen in Hong Kong. The fourth section covers a labor demonstration against a Chinese restaurant called House of Chan. Laborers demand recognition of their union by the employer.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 55 minutes
  - Video 227: CCTV, February 10, 1980; Cuid9273 (Box 91, Video Cuid9273)
    This episode includes two parts: a travel program and coverage of a ceremony in New York City. The first part is a program called Travelogue (), the host introduces a skate rink in Coney Island in New York City, presumably the Abe Stark. Interviews with some skaters are included. The second part covers a ceremony in which President of the City Council Carol Bellamy presents awards to community art groups, including CCTV. The ceremony is held at the Marble Collegiate Church, 1 West 29th Street.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 61 minutes
  - Video 228: CCTV, February 17, 1980; Cuid9274 (Box 91, Video Cuid9274)
    This episode features activities of Chinese people in New York City celebrating the lunar new year. Activities shown in the episode include singing and dancing shows, martial arts (Kung Fu), and a lion dance performance. The episode also includes interviews with the performers. In the last part, the host of the episode tells traditional stories relevant to the Chinese lunar new year (Year of the Monkey).
  - Video 229: CCTV, February 24, 1980; Cuid9275 (Box 91, Video Cuid9275)
    This episode includes three parts: a segment on First Lady Rosalynn Carter's visit to Chinatown, another on a Yale University professor visiting Chinatown with students, and a feature on a Chinese culinary school. In the first part, a banquet is held in a Chinese restaurant to receive Mrs. Carter's visit; Mrs. Carter and others give speeches. The second part includes interviews with the Yale professor - who is Chinese - and the students. The third part features a special program called At Your Service (), which introduces culinary and English lessons offered by the China Institute. Interviews with the institute organizer and culinary lesson participants are included.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 58 minutes
  - Video 230: CCTV, March 2, 1980; Cuid9276 (Box 91, Video Cuid9276)
    This episode includes four parts: street interviews, a lunar new year festival show, a banquet dinner, and an interview with a lawyer. In the first part, the hosts ask people what their views are on the robbery of Chinatown Lincoln Savings Bank. The second part presents a lunar new year performance show organized by the Better Chinatown Project (). The third part features a banquet organized by the Chinese American Chamber of Commerce to welcome Winter Olympic athletes from the People's Republic of China. Interviews with athletes are included. The last part is an interview with Benjamin Gim, a representative of the Chinese Lawyers Association.
  - Video 231: CCTV, March 9, 1980; Cuid9277 (Box 92, Video Cuid9277)
    This episode includes three parts: a segment on First Lady Rosalynn Carter's visit to Chinatown, street interviews, and a 29-minute documentary. In the first part, a banquet is held at the Silver Palace restaurant to receive Mrs. Carter's visit. Mrs. Carter and other Chinese representatives give speeches. This is the first time the First Lady of the United States visits Chinatown for presidential election fundraising. In the second part, two hosts comment on the disadvantages of smoking and interview people about their views on smoking. The third part is a PBS documentary Emi (1979). The other name of the documentary is Pearls. It is directed by Michael Uno and Frank Nesbitt, about Japanese-American Emiko Tonooka's experience in a California concentration camp during World War Two.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 59 minutes
  - Video 232: CCTV, March 16, 1980; Cuid9278 (Box 92, Video Cuid9278)
    This episode includes three parts: interviews with children, a segment on a fundraising banquet, and a 35-minute film. In the first part, two hosts interview children and teenagers about their views on watching television. The second part is about a banquet held in Chinatown to support Ted Kennedy running for the presidential election. Present at the banquet include congressman John Murphy, and New York state Kennedy for president campaign manager Richard Donahue. The third part is a Curtis Choy film Dupont Guy: The Schiz of Grant Avenue (1976). The film narrates the struggles and experiences of being Chinese American.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 62 minutes
  - Video 233: CCTV, March 23, 1980; Cuid9279 (Box 92, Video Cuid9279)
    This episode includes five parts: a segment on the visit of a Shanghai acrobatic theater, an interview with Chinese playwright Cao Yu (), coverage of an academic conference, and a special program on the 1980 census. The first part is about the Shanghai acrobatic troupe's US-tour show. The second part covers Chinese playwright Cao Yu's visit to Columbia University. An interview with Cao Yu is also included. The third part is about a conference organized by Asian Women United, a New York-based women's organization. The fourth part is a performance by Chinese singer Zi Wei (), who is also interviewed. Lastly, the episode includes advertisements to promote the 1980 census, with a special program on the history and operation of census (including interviews with census workers).
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 49 minutes
  - Video 234: CCTV, March 30, 1980; Cuid9280 (Box 92, Video Cuid9280)
    This episode includes three parts: a special program about the 1980 census, a performance, and street interviews. In the first part, the host interviews three census program staff members. They introduce the mission, data collection process, and privacy protection measures of the 1980 census. The second part features a performance by singer Zi Wei (). The third part includes street interviews with Chinatown residents about their views on the 1980 census.
  - Video 235: CCTV, April 3, 1980; Cuid9281 (Box 92, Video Cuid9281)
    This episode is a special program on an acrobatic troupe from Shanghai and their visit to the United States. Included in this episode are stage performances, a reception organized by Chinatown residents to welcome the members, and advertisements of a number of Chinatown stores sponsoring the program.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 54 minutes
  - Video 236: CCTV, April 6, 1980; Cuid9282 (Box 92, Video Cuid9282)
    This episode has four parts: a report on an award presentation banquet in Chinatown, an interview with a Chinese playwright, street interviews, and a special program. In the first part, a banquet is held at the Silver Palace restaurant where the Council of Asian-American Women presents an award to Congresswoman Elizabeth Holtzman. Holtzman is interviewed about her views on immigration and refugee issues. The second part is an interview with Chinese playwright Cao Yu (). There are scenes from stage performances of Cao Yu's works - the English version of Sunrise () and Peking Man (). In the third part, a host interviews Chinatown residents about their views on the 1980 New York City transit strike. The last section is a special program about the 1980 census. The host interviews three census program staff members, asking them to provide details on the purpose and operation of the census.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 57 minutes
  - Video 237: CCTV, April 20, 1980; Cuid9283 (Box 92, Video Cuid9283)
    This episode has four parts: a coverage of an award presentation banquet in Chinatown, excerpts of a cultural festival, a feature report about a vocational training school, and interviews with teenagers. In the first part, a banquet is held at the Silver Palace restaurant where the Council of Asian-American Women presents an award to Congresswoman Elizabeth Holtzman. Holtzman is interviewed about her views on immigration and refugee issues. The second part shows excerpts of a music cultural festival held at Shuang Wen School located in Manhattan's Chinatown. The third part is a feature program called At Your Service (), which covers a hotel management vocational training school. The school is operated by Jack Han. In the last part of this episode, two hosts interview children and teenagers about their views on watching television.
  - Video 238: CCTV, April 27, 1980; Cuid9284 (Box 92, Video Cuid9284)
    This episode includes four sections: street interviews, excerpts of a cultural performance, a travel program, and interviews with martial art performers. The first part includes street interviews with Chinatown residents. Interviewees express views on the changes of Chinatown, such as the expansion of the Chinese population, and the increasing number of stores and garment manufacture factories. The second part shows excerpts of Chinese Cultural Center's performance at Murry Bergtraum High School. The third part is a program called Travelogue (). In this episode, Sheepshead Bay in New York City, New York state is introduced. The fourth section introduces a martial art school in Chinatown. The host interviews the school master and Chinese traditional dancing lion performers.
  - Video 239: CCTV, May 4, 1980; Cuid9285 (Box 92, Video Cuid9285)
    This episode features videos created by participants of CCTV's Production and Performance Workshop held in 1979, the fourth of such sessions. Videos include an advertisement for ballpoint pens, street interviews, a cooking lesson, and a short drama. Interviews with the workshop trainees are also included in this episode.
  - Video 240: CCTV, May 11, 1980; Cuid9286 (Box 93, Video Cuid9286)
    This episode has three parts: a travel program, a social service program, and a feature report on a Chinese singer. The first part is a program called Travelogue (). This episode features the Brooklyn Botanical Garden. The second part is Hello Mother (), in which the hosts interview Ms. Kwan about cosmetic and makeup skills. After the interview, Ms. Kwan has a makeup demonstration. The third part of the video features singing performances by Chinese singer Zi Wei ().
  - Video 241: CCTV, May 18, 1980; Cuid9287 (Box 93, Video Cuid9287)
    This episode includes five sections: a feature report on a labor strike, street interviews, a cultural program, an interview with Chinese playwright Cao Yu (), and a 13-minute Hong Kong documentary. The first part features a labor strike outside Silver Palace Restaurant in Chinatown. An unequal allocation of tips is the main issue. In the second part, hosts interview Chinatown residents about their views on the Silver Palace Restaurant labor strike. The third part features a special program called Asian American Experience, in which Asian-American young people are preparing for the American Heritage Week exhibition. The fourth section covers interviews with Chinese playwright Cao Yu. The fifth section of the episode shows documentary Old Man and His Painting () (1977), in which Chinese painter Ting Yin Yung ()'s life in Hong Kong is documented.
  - Video 242: CCTV, May 24, 1980; Cuid9288 (Box 93, Video Cuid9288)
    This episode includes three parts: a coverage of a cultural activity, a social service program, and a feature report of a martial arts contest. The first part covers the second Annual Asian-Pacific American Heritage Festival held at Lincoln Center. The second part is a program called At Your Service (), in which the Chinatown Daycare Center is featured. The third part features a martial arts contest.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 60 minutes
  - Video 243: CCTV, June 1, 1980; Cuid9289 (Box 93, Video Cuid9289)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature report on a film festival and coverage of a martial arts contest. The first part features the third annual Asian American International Film Festival which is co-sponsored by New York University film school and Asian CineVision. Also included in this episode are excerpts from films of the film festival: Prince Nezha's Triumph Against Dragon King () (1979), Chinese American Second Century, The New Wife, and China: The Land of My Father. The second part of the episode reports a martial arts contest.
  - Video 244: CCTV, June 8, 1980; Cuid9290 (Box 93, Video Cuid9290)
    This episode includes four parts: a feature report on a film festival, coverage of a cultural activity in New Jersey, a dance performance, and interviews with CCTV workshop participants. The first section features the opening ceremony of the third annual Asian American International Film Festival which is held at the Tishman Auditorium at New York University. Excerpts of selected film festival films are also included in the episode. The second part is a report on an Asian cultural activity held in New Jersey. The third part covers Chinese classical dance performances at Murry Bergtraum High School. The fourth section includes interviews with participants at CCTV's fifth Production and Performance Workshop.
  - Video 245: CCTV, June 29, 1980; Cuid9291 (Box 93, Video Cuid9291)
    This episode includes four parts: a feature on a theatrical production, a social service program, a travel program, and street interviews. The first part features the Four Seas Players at Pace University in an adaptation of the 18th century drama work Beggar's Opera. The second part is a feature program called At Your Service (). In this section, a hotel management vocational training school is introduced. The school is operated by Jack Han. The third part is a program called Travelogue (), and features the Bronx Zoo. In the fourth section, Chinatown residents are interviewed about their views on roller skating.
  - Video 246: CCTV, July 6, 1980; Cuid9292 (Box 93, Video Cuid9292)
    This episode includes three parts: coverage of a cultural activity, a social service program, and street interviews. The first part features cultural performances at Pace University organized by a Hong Kong students association. The second part is a special program called At Your Service () which introduces culinary and English lessons offered by China Institute. Interviews with the institute's organizer and lesson participants are included. In the third segment, two hosts interview people about their views on current television programs and their demands for Chinese television programs.
  - Video 247: CCTV, July 13, 1980; Cuid9293 (Box 93, Video Cuid9293)
    This episode includes three parts: a special program on a culture activity, a feature on a Hong Kong performance troupe's visit to New York, and coverage of a Chinatown cultural festival. The first part is a special program called Asian American Experience featuring a New York Shakespeare Festival Workshop theatrical production of FOB. The play is written by David Henry Hwang and stars Calvin Jung, John Lone, and Ginny Yang. The second part of the episode is a program called Hello Mother (). Included in this program are excerpts of Cantonese opera performed at the Sun Sing Theater by Hong Kong's Kam Lai Wah opera troupe (). Interviews with leading performers Lam Kam Tong () and Ng Kwun-Lai () are also included. The third part covers the 10th Chinatown Summer Cultural Festival.
  - Video 248: CCTV, July 20, 1980; Cuid9294 (Box 93, Video Cuid9294)
    This episode includes three parts: a report of an exhibition, street interviews, and a feature on the visit of a Hong Kong performance troupe. The first part covers the 1980 China Decorative Arts Exhibition, held at the United Nations Headquarters in New York City. The second part includes street interviews with people about their views on the increasing cost of living in New York City. The third part features Hong Kong Chor Fung Ming Cantonese Opera troupe ( ) and their performances in the United States. Also included in this part are interviews with leading performers: Siu Chung-kwan (), Lung Kim Sang (), Mui Suet Sze (), Chu Kim Tang () and Yin Suet Fun (), and with the troupe's managers, So Siu-Tong () and Wong Har-wai ().
  - Video 249: CCTV, July 27, 1980; Cuid9295 (Box 94, Video Cuid9295)
    This episode includes three parts: a segment on social services in Chinatown, a report on a cultural festival, and a feature about a performance troupe. The first part is a program called At Your Service () in which the Chinatown Daycare Center is featured. The second part is called Asian American Experience and covers the 1980 New York Obon Festival, a cultural event that celebrates Japanese traditional culture. The third part features the Hai Jia performance troupe (), originally from the Republic of China. Also included in the episode are the troupe's performing shows during their U.S. tour and interviews with the troupe members.
  - Video 250: CCTV, August 3, 1980; Cuid9296 (Box 94, Video Cuid9296)
    This episode includes three parts: a feature on a singing contest, street interviews, and a travel program. The first section is a feature report on a CCTV-sponsored singing competition held at Murry Bergtraum High School. Candidates sing songs in Mandarin and Cantonese. The second part consists of street interviews with people about their views on sanitation issues in Chinatown. The third part is a program called Travelogue (), in which Sheepshead Bay, a neighborhood in New York City, is featured.
  - Video 251: CCTV, August 10, 1980; Cuid9297 (Box 94, Video Cuid9297)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature on a public broadcasting conference, and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. The first part features the first National Conference of Asian Pacific Producers in Public Broadcasting. Excerpts of meetings and discussion sessions are included. The second part is an Allen Fong () film The Wild Child () (1977). The film depicts the life of a young boy living with his grandmother in a rural village.
  - Video 252: CCTV, August 17, 1980; Cuid9298 (Box 94, Video Cuid9298)
    This episode includes four parts: a feature on a Peking opera troupe, a feature on culinary shows, a report on a martial arts performance, and a short documentary. The first part features the U.S. tour of a Peking opera troupe. Excerpts of the troupe's rehearsal are included. In the second part, culinary shows are introduced. The shows take place in Silver Palace Restaurant in Chinatown, by a number of chefs originated from Pan Xi Restaurant (), Guangzhou, People's Republic of China. The third part of the episode covers a martial arts show. The fourth section is a documentary that includes works by Chinese painter Huang Binhong ().
  - Video 253: CCTV, August 24, 1980; Cuid9299 (Box 94, Video Cuid9299)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature on culinary shows, and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. In the first part, culinary shows are introduced. The shows take place in Silver Palace Restaurant in Chinatown, performed by a number of chefs originated from Pan Xi Restaurant, Guangzhou, People's Republic of China. The second part is an Allen Fong () film Song of Yuen Chau Chai () (1977), which depicts the lives of fishermen in Hong Kong.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 50 minutes
  - Video 254: CCTV, September 14, 1980; Cuid9300 (Box 94, Video Cuid9300)
    This episode features a martial art performance show at The Yung Wing Public School in Chinatown. The performance is led by Hong Kong martial art master Shih Kien ().
  - Video 255: CCTV, September 21, 1980; Cuid9301 (Box 94, Video Cuid9301)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature on Chinese puppet show, and a 35-minute film. The first part features Chinese traditional puppet shows performed by the Quanzhou puppet troupe from Fujian Province, People's Republic of China. The troupe is doing a U.S. tour and had four shows at the American Museum of Natural History in New York City. The second part of the episode is a Curtis Choy film Dupont Guy: The Schiz of Grant Avenue (1976). The film narrates the struggles and experiences of being Chinese American.
  - Video 256: CCTV, October 5, 1980; Cuid9302 (Box 94, Video Cuid9302)
    This episode features a 1979 martial arts competition sponsored by CCTV. The participants are of different ethnicities and are practitioners and students from different martial art schools.
  - Video 257: CCTV, October 19, 1980; Cuid9303 (Box 94, Video Cuid9303)
    This episode includes four sections: a brief report on a commerce forum, a feature on the visit of a Hong Kong performance troupe, a travel program, and a 13-minute Hong Kong documentary. The first section is a brief report on the U.S. Secretary of Commerce Philip Klutznick as he attends a forum organized by Chinese American commerce organization to discuss Sino-US trade relations. The second part features Hong Kong Chor Fung Ming Cantonese Opera troupe ()'s operatic performing shows in the United States. Also included in this part are interviews with leading performers: Siu Chung-kwan (), Lung Kim Sang (), Mui Suet Sze (), Chu Kim Tang () and Yin Suet Fun (), and with troupe manager: So Siu-Tong (),Wong Har-wai (). The third part is program called Travelogue () in which the host introduces a skate rink in Brooklyn, New York, presumably the Abe Stark Rink of Coney Island. The fourth part shows documentary Old Man and His Painting () (1977), in which Chinese painter Ting Yin Yung ()'s life in Hong Kong is documented.
  - Video 258: CCTV, October 26, 1980; Cuid9304 (Box 95, Video Cuid9304)
    This episode includes two parts: a report on President Jimmy Carter's Chinatown visit and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. In the first part, Jimmy Carter attends a fundraising banquet held in Silver Palace Restaurant and gives a speech. Interviews with Chinatown residents and banquet participants are also included. The second part is an Allen Fong () film Song of Yuen Chau Chai () (1977), which depicts the lives of fishermen in Hong Kong.
  - Video 259: CCTV, November 2, 1980; Cuid9305 (Box 95, Video Cuid9305)